samford.edu 2018-12-18

# Samford University Website Privacy Policy

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for Samford University ("the university", "we", "our" or "us") and applies solely to the information collected by [www.samford.edu](https://www.samford.edu/) (the site).

Please read this policy carefully before using the site. By using the site, you signify your consent to this privacy policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this privacy policy, please do not use the site.

## Overview

This policy is intended to help you understand the following:

  * What information we collect, how it is used and with whom it may be shared.
  * What choices you have regarding the use of your data.
  * The security procedures in place to protect your information.
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in your information.

## Information Collection

### Non-Personal Information Collection

#### Analytics Cookies

These cookies automatically collect anonymous information that allows us to improve the usefulness and usability of our site by enabling us to troubleshoot problems, understand how visitors found us, the information they value and the tasks that are important to them. These cookies do not personally identify you. However, if you do not want to share anonymous data with us, please visit our site using your browser's incognito or private browsing mode.

#### Advertising Cookies

We have also enabled pixel tracking technologies from advertising platforms like Google and Facebook. These cookies create an advertising profile for your browser and device that allows us to serve more relevant advertisements for our products and services on partner sites. These third-party services may use cookies, web beacons and other similar methods to collect information, provide analytics and target ads. If you do not want to receive personalized ads, you can [opt out of ad personalization from participating partners](https://optout.aboutads.info/), enable "do not track" and disable third-party cookies or visit our site using your browser's incognito or private browsing mode.

### Personal Information Collection

We also provide opportunities for you to voluntarily share personal information such as your name, email address or phone number when they are needed to provide you with information, products or services you are requesting. You will know when you're sharing personal information because you will have to perform an action like submitting a form, sending an email or calling a phone number.

## Information Use

### Non-Personal Information Use

The university uses non-personally-identifiable information to help us better understand our various audiences, how they found the site, what technologies they are using and how they interacted with the site during their visits. Understanding audience engagement helps us make decisions regarding our services and assists us in improving the visitor experience.

### Personal Information Use

The university primarily uses the personal information you provide to fulfill your requests, but we may also contact you via email or present advertisements on third-party sites through the Google Content Network or social media platforms like Facebook, Twitter and Instagram to inform you of university products and services.

## Information Sharing

The university is the sole owner of information collected on our site. While we may share non-personally identifiable information at our discretion, we will not rent or sell your personal information to anyone.

We may share personally identifiable information with partners who are providing services on our behalf. However, our partners are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing services on our behalf.

We may share personally identifiable information with law enforcement agencies, courts, other government authorities or other third parties where we believe it is necessary to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation, or otherwise to protect our rights or the rights of any third party.

## Access to and Control over Your Information

You have certain rights regarding the personal information we hold about you, subject to local law. These may include the rights to access, correct, delete, restrict or object to our use of, or receive a portable copy in a usable electronic format of your personal information. You also may have a right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection or privacy regulator.

### Limit the Information You Share

You have several options to limit the information you share with us (and other websites).

  * Block cookies in your browser.
  * Browse our site using your browser's _private_ or _incognito_ mode.
  * Enable _do not track_ in your browser.
  * Manage your ad preference settings for [Google](https://www.google.com/settings "Manage your Google advertising settings.") and [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads "Manage your Facebook ad preferences.").
  * Do not submit forms, send emails or make calls through the website.

### Limit the Information You Receive

  * Emails from the university should include an _unsubscribe_ link that will allow you to manage the email you receive. If you receive an email that doesn't allow you to unsubscribe, please forward a copy of the email to [webservices@samford.edu](mailto:webservices@samford.edu?subject=Unsubscribe "Forward a copy of the email to Web Services.").
  * Request removal from our customer relation management system by sending an email to [privacy@samford.edu](mailto:privacy@samford.edu?CRM%20Removal%20Request "Request removal from our customer relation management system.").

## Security

Personal information is collected and transmitted over a secure (encrypted) connection. While we take great care to protect your personal information, we acknowledge that no information system can be 100% secure and cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information.

In addition to securing your information during digital transmission, we also protect your information offline by limiting access to employees who need the information to perform a specific job like billing or customer service. 

## Policy Changes

The university may modify or update this privacy policy from time to time. We encourage you to remain informed by checking this page regularly for the latest changes.

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about your privacy. If you believe that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, please contact us immediately by calling [205-726-4144](tel://+12057264144 "Call us to inquire about our privacy policy or report a problem.") or emailing [privacy@samford.edu](mailto:privacy@samford.edu?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Inquiry "Contact us to make an inquiry about our privacy policy or report a problem. ").
